淮阳品尚私人影咖欢迎您
Welcome to huaiyang pinshang private cinema
提示：请勿擅自操作设备
包间内请勿吸烟及使用外带食品
“品尚私人影咖”全体员工祝您观影愉快
我受不了你喋喋不休地唠叨
I'm tired of this constant nagging.
你想变成你姐姐似的
It's like you're turning into one of your sisters.
我厌倦了你的酗酒和自艾自怜
And I'm tired of your drinking and feeling sorry for yourself.
我自艾自怜
Feeling sorry for myself?
♪ I'll be the mechanic of your heart... ♪
观在一大批失业
Half the bloody country is out of work.
你又不特别 哦 让我出去
You're not that special. Oh, let me out of here.
♪ And with a wrench, I'll take you apart... ♪
这是我家 你家 太荒唐了
It's my bloody house. Your bloody house? Brilliant.
我还了15年的房贷
I've been paying the mortgage on it for the last 15 years.
要是你不还的话 我会离开你
If we didn't share a mortgage, I would leave you.
♪ If we didn't share a mortgage ♪
♪ I would leave you... ♪
我受够了 随你吧
I've had enough of it. Go on and leave any time you like.
♪ Go on and leave any time you like... ♪
随你 贱人
Go on then, you stupid bitch.
♪ You stupid bitch... ♪
虽然目前还没有准确的数据
Though there are still no accurate figures
到底有多少爱尔兰年轻人来到英国找工作
for the number of young lrish people coming to London
但粗略估计呈上升趋势
in search of work, the crude indications that do exist show an enormous increase.
有人带一点钱坐船过来
Many take the boat with barely enough money
在伦敦生活一段时间 但一部分人会选择移民
to survive a few days in London, but still they emigrate
因为他们在这看到了希望 而这些希望在爱尔兰是看不到的
because they see hope across the sea, hope they cannot see in lreland.
要开会了
This meeting has been called to order.
拜托能快点
Pray proceed.
你们有人可能已经注意到了
Well, as some of you may have noticed,
这些天来我和你们妈妈承受着巨大压力
your mother and I really are under a lot of pressure at the moment.
跟这个国家里的其他的人一样
Like the rest of the country.
我今年没什么活
I haven't had a single commission this year.
你们妈妈工作也减少到了一周三天
Your mother is down to a three-day week.
看起来不大有希望好转
It doesn't look like it's going to get much brighter.
我们看了一下存款
So we had a look at our accounts,
嗯 得改变一下教育状况
and... well, we-we see we could make a significant saving
我们才能坚持下去
if we altered the education situation.
什么教育状况
What education situation?
她是说你的学校
- Well... - She means your school.
他们想让你辍学
They're taking you out of school.
什么 不行
- What? - No, no.
我们不会让你停学的
We're not taking you out of school.
我们给你换一家学校
We're transferring you from one school
换所学校 为什么
- to another school. - Why?
因为我们要节省开支
Because we need to make some cuts in the budget somewhere.
我们想让你哥哥放弃大学学业
I'd suggest taking your brother out of college,
但他早就自作主张不读了
but he's already dropped out of his own volition.
谢谢你 罗伯特
Thank you, Robert.
基督教兄弟会的教育质量不错
The Christian Brothers have a fine history of education.
谁是基督教兄弟会
Who are the Christian Brothers?
是一个教育机构
The Christian Brothers are an educational institution
康纳 这是基督教兄弟成立
- formed by... - The Christian Brothers, Conor,
是由天主教自行管理的
are an order of the Catholic Church self-appointed in their education formation
由年轻人自行管理
and systematic beating of their young charges.
哦 闭嘴 布兰登
Oh, shut up, Brendan.
在耶稣会读的六年 你都被教成什么样了
Six years in the hands of the Jesuits, and look what they did for you.
康纳 你必须要面对它
You're just gonna have to face up to this, Conor.
你知道他们的格言是什么吗
Do you know what the Christian Brothers' motto is?
男子气
"Viriliter Age."
你知道是什么意思吗
Do you know what that means?
欺凌学生
"Let's rape our students"?
不 布兰登 不是那样的
No, Brendan, it doesn't.
意思是 像男人一样
It means "act manly."
你在做什么 别挡道
What are you doing? Get out of the bleedin' way.
早上好 巴克斯特兄弟
Morning, Brother Baxter.
坐下
Sit down.
是法语 巴纳巴斯兄弟
- French, Brother Barnabas. - Huh?
你是教法语 不是拉丁语
You're teaching French, not Latin.
哦 我太现代化了
Oh, how modern.
注意 如果你们中有人知道法国在哪
Mind you, I'd be surprised if any of you knew where France is,
却不会说法语的话 我会很吃惊的
not to mind speaking the language.
哦 讲
Oh, go on.
在大陆上
It's on the continent.
在西班牙上面
Above Spain.
你是那个新家伙 从耶稣会转来的
You'll be the new lad, then, from the Jesuits.
你叫什么
What's your name?
康纳·劳乐
Conor Lawlor.
康纳·劳乐 安静
- Ooh! -Conor Lawlor? - Shut up!
对了 康纳 9 : 00做早祷告
Right, Conor. Morning prayers are at quarter to 9:00.
食堂就在体育馆下面
The canteen is located just below the PE hall.
提供薯条和巧克力
They serve chips and bars.
我们这里严格规定必须穿黑色鞋子 劳乐
We have a strict black-shoe policy here, Mr. Lawlor.
你父母给你的校规介绍的本子里都到这一条了吧 在142页
Your parents should have read it in the introductory rule book, page 142.
我没有黑鞋子
I don't have black shoes, sir.
那你得去买一双了
Well, you're just going to have to get a pair then, aren't you?
买了以后马上向我汇报
And report to me first thing in the morning with them.
好小伙
Good man.
教士
Brother.
我们接着上课
As you were.
打扰一下
Sorry.
他说餐厅在哪来着
Where did he say the restaurant was again?
你是说食堂吗
Do you mean the canteen?
是的 食堂 对
Of course, the can-canteen, yeah.
餐厅
"The restaurant."
你现在不在法国了 死娘炮
You're not in France now, you bleedin' spanner.
吸烟吗
Do you smoke?
偶尔会
- Do you? - Occasionally.
我不怎么抽烟
I'm not really a smoker.
我哥哥总抽  有时我和我朋友会偷他的抽
My brother is. Uh, sometimes steal a bit of his tobacco when my friends are over.
你想吸吗 还是
So do you want to have a smoke then or...?
-在这 -来我们吸烟去 跟我来
- Here? -Come on, we'll have a smoke. Come on, follow me.
来Come on.
来一根吗
Here, do you want one?
我不需要
Nah, I'm okay.
早上已经抽了两根了
I already had two this morning.
看这
Actually, look at this yoke.
这是黑寡妇
It's a Black Widow.
非常狂野
Savage.
-我听说你是个怪人 -什么
- Now, I hear you're a queer. - What?
没错 我听说你有点古怪
Yeah, I hear you're a little queer.
不 你一定认错人了
No, you must have me mixed up with someone else.
我不那么认为
Nah, I don't think so.
跳舞
Dance.
- Dance? - Dance!
像个怪人一样跳舞
Dance, like a little queer, go.
你是在开玩笑吗
Are you joking?
快速抖动
Jig.
动起来
Move it.
不 手动起来
No, more arms.
对 迪斯科
Uh, yeah, disco, kind of.
脱裤子跳舞
Now dance with your pants down.
啥
What?
嗯去那个小隔间 脱裤子跳
Hmm. Get into that cubicle, dance with your pants down.
不
No.
你说什么
What did you just say?
我不会那样做的
Uh, I'm not, I'm not doing that.
今天是周四
It's Thursday.
现在晚上7点
It's 7:00.
这里是 流行前线
It's Top of the Pops.
康纳 布兰登 过来 7点了
Conor, Brendan, come on, it's 7:00!
他们在美国 今天不能来这
They can't be here tonight, as they are in the USA,
我们要去里约
so instead we have to go to Rio.
这是Duran Duran
It's Duran Duran.
嘿 我们在这用功呢
Hey, we're working here.
我们也是
So are we.
这是我的作业 布莱登
This is my homework, Brendan.
我明早之前一定要把这篇重要的论文写出来
I have a really important essay due in the morning.
你要放弃梦想 不代表我们也要
Just because you've given up on your dreams doesn't mean we have to, all right?
能吸烟吗
Can we put the fire on?
不能
No.
你会爱上这的
You're gonna love this, man.
对 漂亮
Yes! Beautiful.
不敢确定这些家伙能发展成什么样
The jury's still out on which way these guys'll go,
但他们很有趣 那个约翰·泰勒
but they're a lot of fun, and John Taylor
是现在英国最专业的贝斯手
is one of the most proficient bass players in the UK at the moment.
让他们乐队非常有放克范 我也希望他们能朝这个方向发展
Gives them a really funky edge, which I hope they're gonna go for.
嘿 不就是跟披头士乐队一样吗
Hey, it's not exactly the Beatles, is it?
康纳 你出去把时光机器打开
Oh, you know, will you go outside and start up
可以跟老爸一起回到过去
the time machine there so we can all go back in time
如果这是将来的话
- for Dad, Conor. - Well, if this is the future,
那我们就都完蛋了 我是说 看那家伙
we're all screwed, aren't we? I mean, look at this guy.
他都甚至不是现场唱的
He's not even singing live.
这是音乐录像带 罗伯特
It's a video, Robert.
是艺术
It's art.
这是现在的主流 看那
Everybody's making them these days. Look at it.
他很有魅力 不是吗
He's very attractive, though, isn't he?
他会喜欢你的
You're welcome to him.
希望是
Promise?
那个吉他手是谁
Who's that guitarist?
约翰·泰勒
John Taylor.
所有女孩都迷他
All the girls love him.
很帅吧 安
Cute, isn't he, Ann?
并且 不是吉他手
And he's not a guitarist.
他是个贝斯手 对
- He's a bassist. - Yeah, Ann.
为什么就不现场直播
I mean, why can't they get them to play live?
他们要隐藏什么吗
What are they trying to hide?
因为他们在美国
It's because they're in the USA.
听说过吗
Did you not hear him?
而且这个会一直流传下去的
And this lasts forever.
这就是音乐和电视的最完美的结合
It's the perfect mixture of music and visuals.
很短 但是很给力
It's short, to the point.
看
Look at it.
我说 对这东西根本就不能拒绝啊
I mean, what tyranny could stand up to that?
早上好 劳乐
Good morning, Mr. Lawlor.
嗯 我和妈妈说了 但她说
Well, I brought it up with my mum, but she said
我们家现在没钱再买一双鞋
we can't afford another pair at the moment.
这双鞋是我在知道校规前
I bought these before I knew about the shoe color policy
在辛格街买的
here at Synge Street.
又不是跑步鞋
But it's not as if they're runners or something.
虽然是棕色的
They're... they're brown.
但也不是大问题嗄
They're-they're quite sensible.
但颜色是不是黑色
They're not black.
我不是很清楚你的意思
I'm-I'm not sure what you want me to do.
把它们脱下来
Take them off.
把它放在那边门那里
You can leave them at the door there.
看在你很爱这双鞋的份上 你可以每天4点来这把它拿走
Seeing as you're so fond of them, you can pick them up here at 4:00 every day
直到你愿意遵守校规为止
until you comply with the rules of the school.
什么？
What?
再见
See you.
来跟玛氏棒
Could I have a Mars bar, please?
25便士
25p.
谢谢
Thank you.
看这
Here.
哦
Ooh!
你应该跳舞的
You should've just danced.
那个神经病是谁
Who is that psycho?
他叫巴尔里·布雷
That's Barry Bray.
他能烦你一年 为什么
- He'll be out for your blood for the year. -Why?
因为你看上去很弱
'Cause you've shown signs of weakness.
你是怎么认识他的
So how do you know him?
他和我住在同一幢公寓
He lives in the same flat as me.
他妈妈爸爸都吸毒
His ma and da are drugs addicts.
但别担心
But don't worry.
你只需好好计划一下你这一年
You just need to come up with a plan for the year.
一个方案
A solution.
给你
Here.
核对一下
Check it out.
达伦·马尔韦 商业计划
"Darren Mulvey Business Solutions."
随时找我
Call me anytime.
但上面没写电话
There's no number on it.
哦不 不是打电话
Oh, no, we don't have a phone.
随时来找我
Just call around, yeah?
她是谁
Who's she?
我不知道
I don't know.
她老在那
She's always there.
她很漂亮
She's beautiful.
没错 长得不错
Yeah, good luck.
她不和任何人说话
She doesn't speak to anyone.
傲慢的家伙
Stuck-up cow.
她说她的男朋友是个毒贩
She said her boyfriend's a drug dealer.
他对学校的男孩子都不感兴趣
She's not interested in any of the boys in school.
那她每天早上站在那做什么
Then why is she standing over there every morning, then?
要火吗
Need a light?
不 我正要把它戒掉
No. I'm trying to give up.
反正我也没有火柴
I don't have any matches anyway.
你为什么不在学校
So, how come you're not in school?
我不上学
I don't go to school.
我是个模特
I'm a model.
酷 给杂志做模特吗
Cool, like, for magazines?
我很快要到伦敦去了
I'm going to London soon.
在等我商业拍照
Just waiting for my portfolio shots.
在都柏林没什么事做 你知道的
There's no real work for models in Dublin, you know?
嗯 可不是吗
Yeah, tell me about it.
你想出现在录像里吗
Do you want to be in a video?
为我的乐队
It's for my band.
你有个乐队啊
You're in a band?
是的 我们需要一个女孩
Yes, and we need a girl for it.
你之前有录制过录像吗
Have you ever been in a video before?
没有
No.
有问题吗
Is that a problem?
我希望不是
I hope not.
我得问一下制片人
I'll ask the producer.
谁是制片人
Who's the producer?
后面那小子
That kid behind me.
要是有你的电话的话 我会打电话告诉你详细情况的
I could call you with the details, if I had your digits.
你既然呆在乐队 给我唱首歌吧
So, if you're in a band, sing me a song.
在这唱 恐怕不太好吧
I can't sing out here.
你将来要在成千上万的人面前唱歌
You're gonna have to sing for, like, thousands of people.
我只是其中之一
I'm just one.
快唱
Sing.
别吧
Don't make me sing.
天啊
Jesus.
唱那首在收音机里的
Sing that song off the radio.
A-ha唱的那首
You know, the one by A-ha.
唱吧
Sing it.
唱啊
♪ Take... ♪ Sorry.
♪ Take... ♪
起低了
No, it's too low.
♪ Take on me ♪
♪ Take me on. ♪
只会这几句
That's all I know.
酷 再见
Cool, bye.
我们得组个乐队 什么
- We need to form a band. - What?
好吗 达伦
How are you, Darren?
埃蒙在吗 埃蒙
- Is Eamon there? - Eamon?
嘿 埃蒙
Hey, Eamon.
你最近在干什么
What are you doing?
没干什么
Nothing really.
喂喂小兔子
Just feeding me new bunny.
康纳这是埃蒙 埃蒙 这是康纳
Conor, this is Eamon. Eamon, this is Conor.
康纳是新来的学生 他要组一个乐队
Conor's new in school, and he's putting a band together.
哦天哪
Oh, good Jesus.
所以呢
So?
Wow.
这些你都是哪鼓捣来的
Where'd you get all this gear?
我爸在一个翻唱乐队
Me da's in a covers band.
主要在婚礼 聚会 酒吧表演
Weddings, parties, pubs.
埃蒙会弹各种乐器
Eamon can play every instrument known to mankind.
对吗 埃蒙
Can't you, Eamon?
差不多
Probably.
让他瞧瞧
Show him.
你瞧瞧
Check it.
你觉得
So what do you think...
你觉得你自己适合做什么
So, what do you play yourself?
我是个歌手
I'm more of a singer.
我写歌 填词 作曲
I write songs, words, lyrics.
但还没编成歌
But I haven't put them to music yet.
你要唱哪一类型的歌
What kind of music are yous gonna be doing?
嗯 我还不知道
Well, I-I don't know yet.
什么叫还不知道 你得知道你要唱什么
What d'you mean you don't know? You have to know what you're gonna be playing.
你在搞什么
What are you into?
我是个未来派
I'm a futurist.
什么意思
What does that mean?
不怀旧
Like, uh, no nostalgia.
不像你父亲的乐队
Not like your da's band.
不回头看 向前走
Not looking backwards, just forwards.
哦酷 像Depeche Mode那种吗
Oh, cool. Like Depeche Mode?
对 或者Joy Division那种
- Okay. - Or Joy Division?
对
Right.
Duran Duran这种
Or Duran Duran?
你觉得他们怎么样
What do you think of them?
这些家伙会发展什么样 还不好说
Jury is out on which way those guys'll go.
他们很有趣 詹姆斯·约翰是英国最专业的贝斯手
They're a lot of fun, and James Taylor is one of the most proficient bass players
让他们的乐队非常有放克范儿
in the UK at the moment, giving them a funky edge.
约翰·泰勒
John Taylor.
对 约翰 当然
Yeah, John. Of course.
我会加入你的乐队
I'll be in your band.
我可以弹吉他
I'll play guitar.
我还可以帮忙写歌
And I'll help write songs.
我们可以在这排练 因为我爸在圣约翰
We could rehearse here 'cause my da's in Saint John of Gods.
是个酒吧吗？ 不 达伦
- Is that a pub? - No, Darren.
是个拒绝酒精的地方
It's a place where alcoholics go to get off the drink,
禁止殴打孩子和妇女
stop beating up their wives and kids.
很好
Right.
也不能打邻居
And neighbors.
谁做经理
Who's gonna be the manager?
我
Me.
你之前做过乐队经理吗
Have you managed bands before?
没有 我只闯过超市
No, I'm just breaking into the market.
那我直说了
Got to get everything straight.
什么事情都得有书面合同
Get everything down on paper first.
否则的话唱片公司会让你抓狂的
Otherwise, the major record labels can rip you off when they come hunting.
我爸就是这么说的
That's what me da says.
你想什么时候排练
When'd you want to rehearse?
周末不行
Not at the weekends.
他周六在奎恩斯沃斯有份整理货架的活
He's got a job packing shelves in Quinnsworth on Saturdays.
你不能因为乐队放弃这份工作 听到了吗
You're not giving that up for any band, d'you hear me?
知道了
Yeah.
周一和周三放学后怎么样
What about Mondays and Wednesdays after school?
可以
That's fine.
听起来不错
Sounds good.
我们现在还差一些乐手
Now all we need is other musicians.
你有认识的吗
Do yous know any?
没有 埃蒙
- No. - Eamon?
他通常一个人玩
He usually just plays on his own.
对吗 宝贝
Don't you, love?
对 我们这里什么都做不了
Right, well, we can't get any peace in here.
我们到外面讨论吧
Let's continue this meeting outside.
现在不能抽烟
No smoking now.
妈妈 我到底和你说多少次
Ma, how many times do I have to tell you?
我不抽烟
I don't smoke.
3B班有个黑人
There's a black guy in 3B.
那又怎么样
So?
有他在乐队一定很酷为什么
- Be cool if he was in the band. - Why?
他可能是学校唯一的一个黑人
He's probably the one black guy in the whole school.
可能都柏林也就他一个
Probably in Dublin.
乐队里有个黑鬼会很时髦
Having a golliwog in the band give us a real edge.
你不能说黑鬼
You can't say "golliwog."
为什么不能
Why not?
相信我 别那么说
Trust me, you just can't.
可是他要是什么都不会怎么办
And anyway, what if he can't play anything?
他总会弹点什么 他是黑人呢
He'll be able to play something; he's black.
哇 请问有什么事吗
- Wow. - Can I help you?
那个有色少年住这吗
Is this the house where the colored lad lives?
下面第四扇门
Four doors down.
你们怎么想的
What do you think?
你们觉得这破地方会有多少黑人
How many black people do you think that lives on this shitty estate?
你认识尼吉吗 有什么事吗
- Do you know Ngig? - What's that?
尼吉 我儿子
Ngig. My son.
我们建了个乐队 他会弹乐器吗
We're putting a band together. Does he play any instruments?
你为什么不自己问他
Why don't you ask him yourself?
我们正在
We are putting
组建一个乐队
a band together.
我是经理人
I am the manager.
他有什么毛病吗？
What the hell is wrong with him?
哦 你 和你妈妈声音有点不同
Oh, you, um, sound different from your mam.
那是当然 我坐在这半天了
Course I do; been here half me bleedin' life.
你们有什么事吗
What'd you think?
你有兴趣加入我们乐队吗
Would you have any interest in playing in a band?
你们玩什么类型的音乐
What kind of music are yous playing?
现在还不肯定 你玩乐器吗
We're not a hundred percent sure yet, but do you play any instruments?
可能吧
Maybe.
来来派乐队招募中
"Futurist band forming.
寻找一个贝斯手 鼓手
Looking for a bass player, drummer."
是说我们吗
That's us.
受 Depeche Mode，Duran Duran等乐队影响
"Influences include Depeche Mode, Duran Duran and many more."
-基佬 -滚开 莱恩
- Faggots. - Piss off, Ryan.
联系负责人 圣德维沙 花园361室
"Contact Management Solutions, 361 at St. Theresa's Gardens.
没有电话 敲门就行
No telephone, just call in."
好像就是在找我们
Sounds like a gig for us.
我们走
Let's go.
乐队叫什么名字
So what are we called, then?
对 那
All right, what about...
免子 怎么样
The Rabbits?
你和免子有什么故事吗
What's the story with you and rabbits?
我不知道 只是喜欢兔子
I don't know, I just love them.
拉维 怎么样
What about La Vie?
什么意思
What's that mean?
生活的法语词
It's French for "The Life."
为什么用法语 嗯 那不能做一个乐队的名孚
What's French for, uh, "That's not gonna be the name of the band"?
一个乐队的名字
C'est nes pas le nom du groupe.
你说呢
There you go.
唱街 怎么样
What about... Sing Street?
你们觉得不像吗
Do you actually not get that like?
唱街
Sing Street.
哦 我喜欢
- Oh! - I like that.
不错 嗯 我喜欢
- Gobshites. - Yeah, I like it.
♪ Moving on the floor now, babe ♪
♪ You're a bird of paradise ♪
♪ Cherry ice-cream smile ♪
♪ I suppose it's very nice ♪
♪ Her name is Rio ♪
♪ And she dances on the sand ♪
♪ Just like that river ♪
♪ Twisting through a dusty land ♪
♪ And when she smiles ♪
♪ She really shows you all she can ♪
♪ Oh, Rio, Rio ♪
♪ Dance across the Rio Grande. ♪
最后那部分稍微有点快 是吗
- Sped up a bit there at the end. - Really?
听起来不错 是吗 我们听起来死气沉沉的
- That sounded great. - Yeah, we sound deadly.
少年 我们要疯了
Oh, lads, we're gonna be amazing.
你做什么
What are you doing?
让那讨厌的家伙出去
I'm just letting the stink of that out, man.
Whew.
音乐真差劲
That was bad, bad music.
没有比这更糟的音乐了
And there is nothing as bad in this world as bad music.
这带子还能用的 不
- You know you can record over tapes? -No.
你这就是个半吊子
That was a novelty act.
想交配想疯了吧
You want to have actual sexual intercourse, right?
-什么？ -女孩
- Yeah. What, what? - The girl.
-为了追女孩吧？ -追女孩 对
It's all about the girl, isn't it? - Yeah, the girl, yeah. - And you're gonna use
你想用别人的歌来追到女孩 开玩笑吗
somebody else's art to get her? Are you kidding?
我们才开始
We're just starting.
我们要知道如何演奏
We need to learn how to play.
性手枪乐队知道如何演奏吗
Did the Sex Pistols know how to play?
你不用知道 你谁啊
You don't need to know how to play. Who are you?
斯迪利·丹吗 康纳 你并不要知道如何演奏
Steely Dan? You need to learn how not to play, Conor.
这就是要点 这才摇滚
That's the trick. That's rock and roll.
刻苦训练
And that takes practice.
顺便说一下 你们不是翻唱乐队
And you're not a covers band, by the way.
是吗 不
- Really? - No.
每个学校都有个翻唱乐队
Every school has a covers band.
每个酒吧有个翻唱乐队
Every pub has a covers band.
每场婚礼都有个翻唱乐队
Every wedding has a covers band.
每一个翻唱乐队都有个中年成员
And every covers band has a middle-aged member
他们从不知道自己能否在乐坛取得成功
who'll never know whether they could've made it in the music industry or not
因为他们从没胆量去写一首歌
because they never had the balls to write a song for someone else.
玩摇滚乐有风险
Rock and roll is a risk.
你要做好被嘲笑的准备
You risk being ridiculed.
但是我不会写歌
But I don't know how to write a song.
把那扇门关上 坐下
Close that door and sit down.
是吗 我们来彻夜长谈
- Really? - It's gonna be a long night.
我明天还要上课
I've school in the morning.
现在我给你上课
This is school.
她是角落里乔装打扮的天使
"She's standing on the corner "like an angel in disguise.
我想试着提醒
"I want to try and warn her.
她有一双危险的眼睛
She's got dangerous eyes."
危险的眼睛
"Dangerous eyes."
我喜欢那
I like that.
那是什么意思
What does it mean?
我不知道
I don't know.
这首歌写的什么 康纳
What's the song about, Conor?
这就像你不了解一些人 就会对他们很感兴趣
It's like when you don't know someone, they're more interesting.
他们可以是你心目中的一切
They can be anything you want them to be.
Yeah.
但是当你了解他们之后
But when you know them,
他们就会有这样那样的不足
there's limits to them.
不 那没意义
No, that doesn't make any sense.
歌叫什么名字
What's it called?
模特之谜
"The Riddle of the Model."
这种旋律怎么样
So what about a rhythm like this?
不错
Nice.
稍微放慢一点
Slow it down a little.
Yeah.
对 好棒 就是这样
Yeah, that's cool, that's it.
♪ Standing on the corner ♪
♪ Like an angel in disguise ♪
♪ I wanna try and warn her ♪
♪ She's got dangerous eyes. ♪
我有个主意
I've an idea.
副歌部分 这样
Maybe for the chorus, like, a...
Yeah.
对 然后你可以停一下
Yeah. There you can do a stop.
对 然后我开始唱
- Yeah. - And I come in and sing.
♪ The riddle of the model. ♪
大家都停下来吗
Like, would everybody stop?
对对 每个人都停 像 鼓
- Yeah. Yeah, everyone. - Like, the drums
可以做一个 对
- will do a... - Yeah.
不 我们都停一下
No, yeah. We-we all stop.
烟花和灯光
- Fireworks and lights and shit. I don't know. -Yeah.
每个人 他们都
- Everyone. - And they all...
他们都停下来 疯狂 太酷了
- Everyone stops, yeah. - Crazy shit, that'd be cool.
我喜欢 对 对
- I like that. - Yeah, yeah.
可能像
So maybe like a...
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ The riddle of the model. ♪
对 我喜欢 太棒了
- Yeah. - Yeah, I like that. That's good.
对 很酷 对
- Yeah, that's cool. - Yeah.
你 你有吸尘器吗
Do you, do you have a hoover?
试试效果
Check out this effect.
就像那首“录像杀死了广播播明星”
It's like "Video Killed the Radio Star."
开始
Go.
♪ Standing in the corner ♪
♪ Like an angel in disguise... ♪
Hey.
最近怎么样
How's it going?
啊 这是带子
Uh, here's the tape.
这是什么
What's this?
是一首歌 我和你说过的
Oh, that's the song; I mentioned it to you.
哦 你是那个乐队男孩
Oh, you're the kid in the band.
是的 你可能得学学歌词
Yeah, you should probably learn the lyrics.
所以你可以准确的对嘴型
So you can lip-sync to them properly.
我们准备在奎斯沃斯后面的小巷里拍摄
We're shooting at the lane at the back of Quinnsworth.
你知道奎斯沃斯？ 嗯
- You know Quinnsworth? - Yeah.
这周六12点
This Saturday at 12:00.
不错 好吧 我会尽量去
Cool. Well, I'll try and make it.
到时候我穿什么呢
What would I wear?
我不知道
I don't know.
歌曲比较中国风
It's kind of like a Chinese theme.
所以 要穿和服吗
So, like, a kimono?
乐节有点中国风而已
Well, it's more like a riff than a song.
有点东方气息
More of an Eastern bit in the song.
歌名是“模特之谜”
It's called "The Riddle of the Model."
那真是贴心
That's really sweet.
Oh.
不 这不是关于你的
No, it's not about you.
是关于我认识的另一个模特
It's about another model I know.
Oh.
好吧 我会听的 只是我现在真的 真的很忙
Right, well, I'll give it a listen, but I'm, like, really, really busy at the moment.
你知道的 所以 我会试试
You know, so I'll try.
好 你一定得听 这是首好歌
Yeah, you should. It's a, it's a good song.
我们得团队很棒
We've got a great team.
这真的是一次很好的机会
It's a really good opportunity.
厉害
Cool.
这个星期六12点 说定了哈
So this Saturday at 12:00, then?
12点 听起来不错
12:00. Sounds good.
谢谢你 那好
- Thanks. - Cool.
拜拜
Bye.
家里的装备都带来了 不是吗
Looks like loads of gear back home, doesn't it?
奇怪的是 看起来像一堆废物
And yet, strangely, it just looks like shit here.
没错
Yeah.
嘿  那个小妞呢
Ah, hey, where is this chick?
我不知道
I don't know.
到底是谁 把这身牛仔服带来的
Who the hell brought a cowboy costume?
是我 这是我唯一能找到的了
Me. It's all I could find.
没人会在乐队里穿牛仔服
No one wears a cowboy costume in a band.
在“乡下人” 里就有个牛仔
There's a cowboy in the Village People.
还有亚当·安特
And Adam Ant.
亚当·安特就是个强盗
Adam Ant is a highwayman.
所以我们可以有强盗 为什么不能有牛仔呢
So we can have a highwayman, but we can't have a cowboy?
你精神有问题吗
Are you mentally ill?
我在玩笑商店买了个尖牙
I got fangs in the joke shop.
你准备拿这个干嘛
What are you gonna do with them?
这是段音乐录像 不是什么血腥暴力电影
It's a music video, - not a bleedin' horror film. - Spanner.
你们带了什么衣服
So what did yous bring?
这是我老爸的乐队演出服
It's me da's show band outfit.
所以我们是个基佬乐队
So it's a gay band?
好吧
Okay.
这话是从一个“乡下人”乐队的人说出来的
Coming from the one who wants to look like the Village People.
“乡下人 ”又不是基佬
What's gay about the Village People?
各位好 很抱歉我来晚了
Hello, all. Sorry I'm late.
昨晚我出去了
I was out last night.
一家夜总会
At a nightclub.
天哪 你们穿的都是些什么
Jesus Christ, what are you all wearing?
没错 我们正为这事发愁呢
Yeah, we're just working that out.
嗯 也许你可以帮忙
Um, maybe you can help.
好吧 谁是你们的服装师
Well, who's your costume person?
我们并没有服装师
We don't really have a costume person.
好吧 谁是摄像师
Well, who's your cameraman?
也许他可以做点这方面的事
Maybe he can make some of this work.
好吧 我们也没有
Well, we don't really have...
我是摄像师
I'm the cameraman.
我以为你是制作人
Thought you were the producer.
我还是摄像师
And the cameraman.
不惜一切代价省钱
Saving money at all costs, yeah.
你觉得歌怎么样
What'd you think of the song?
我很喜欢
I really liked it.
这是我唯一愿意来这的原因
It's the only reason I'm here.
这歌是你写的吗
Did you write it?
艾蒙写了大部分的曲
Eamon wrote most of the music.
歌词是你写的
So you wrote the lyrics?
不错
Cool.
你的颧骨生得很好看
You've got really good cheekbones.
什么 没错
- What? - Yeah.
你应该让我来帮你化个妆
Yeah, you should let me do your makeup.
真的吗 没错 这个光线用相机拍出来
- Really? -Yeah. Now this light's gonna be
会非常刺眼
really harsh on camera.
它会减弱边缘的光
It'll take the edge off.
实际上我刚刚化了妆过来
I'm actually wearing some right now.
事实上 你们都得化个妆
In fact, you should all be wearing makeup.
不 我一点妆也不想化
Yeah, I'm not wearing any makeup.
放松 你甚至不在这个乐队里
Relax, you're not even in the band.
没错 谢天谢地
Yeah, thank God.
我在这个乐队里 而我也一点都不想化妆 谢谢
I'm in the band, and I will not be wearing any makeup. Thank you.
为什么 你的嘴唇这么好看
Why? You've got great lips.
不 走开 反正我不要化妆
No, piss off. I'm not wearing makeup.
随便你
Whatever.
你们中如果真的有人关心这个乐队
Those of you who actually care about the band
真心想把这件事情做好的话 去那边排队
and want to do this half properly, queue over there.
好 我们就在这儿演奏
Okay, so we're playing over here,
瑞菲娜站在那边靠着墙
and Raphina's standing over there against the wall.
我向你走去然后开始对着你唱歌
I go up to you and start singing to you.
当我唱到这一句“她有一双危险的眼睛”时确保镜头移向她的眼睛
Make sure to pan up to her eyes when I sing the line, "She's got dangerous eyes."
我觉得来个变焦会更好
I think a zoom would be better.
好变焦也可以
Okay, a zoom, whatever.
你觉不觉得当我闭眼的时候我的眼皮上该显得闪闪的
Do you think I should have, like, lightning flashes on my eyelids when I close 'em?
你会弄这个
Can you do that?
我什么都会做
I can do anything.
厉害
Cool.
副歌部分 你向别处走 我跟着你
So then for the chorus, you walk off and I follow,
围绕着你 好像“颤栗”里那样
circling you like when he's following her in the "Thriller" video.
你有没有看“颤栗” 看过
- Have you seen the "Thriller" video? - Yeah.
很好 之后我跟你走进巷道
Cool. So then I follow you up the laneway,
始终尾随着你 然后转过来拍正面
keeping behind you, and then we'll swing around and get the angle in front.
我们来拍吧 好的 我们开始吧
- Let's shoot it. - Right, let's shoot.
一群小孩在拍些什么东西
It's just some kids filming something.
你们在拍什么 小伙子
What are yous filming, lads?
我们乐队的录像
A video for a band.
你好 巴里
Hi, Barry.
他们是你在学校的同学吗 巴里
Are these in your school, Barry?
对 没错
Yeah, they are, yeah.
但他们画着夸张的妆容
But they're wearing bleedin' makeup.
我知道
I know.
噢 小伙子你们在拍电影 是吗
Oh, yous making a movie, lads, is it?
不是 只是为乐队拍的一段录像
Nah, it's just a video for a band.
你也应该加入乐队 巴里
You should get in a band, Barry.
涂点儿口红 然后跳啊跳
Put on lipstick, dance around and all.
-你一定会很棒的 -滚蛋吧
- You'd be bleedin' great. - Piss off.
你说什么 什么都没说
- What did you say? - Nothin'.
下次再见 小伙们
See yous, lads.
我们奥斯卡见
See yous at the Oscars.
伙伴们 打起精神来
Right, lads, lots of energy in this.
还有 尼基 我想看到你用力地按键
And, Ngig, I want to see you really pressing those keys.
开始放歌了
Here's some playback.
♪ She's standing on the corner ♪
♪ Like an angel in disguise ♪
♪ And as I look a little closer ♪
♪ She's got dangerous eyes ♪
- ♪ She tells me she's a model ♪ - I'm a model.
♪ Of international reputation ♪
♪ She's lightning in a bottle ♪
♪ But there's a stipulation ♪
♪ She's so indecipherable ♪
♪ She holds the key to the missing code ♪
♪ Just the thought of her touch ♪
♪ My mind explodes ♪
♪ So desirable ♪
♪ Time never will unfold ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ The riddle of the model ♪
♪ The odds are against her ♪
♪ In this little city ♪
♪ She's got a taste for adventure ♪
♪ And she knows she's pretty ♪
♪ She's the face of an angel ♪
♪ And the heart of a sinner ♪
♪ And if you play with danger ♪
♪ How you gonna win her? ♪
♪ She's so indecipherable ♪
♪ She holds the key to the missing code ♪
♪ Just the thought of her touch ♪
♪ My mind explodes ♪
♪ So desirable ♪
♪ Time never will unfold ♪
♪ I'll never unravel ♪
♪ The riddle of the model. ♪
我们为什么不去公园吃这些
Why don't we go eat these in the park?
给你的
There you go.
谢谢你 不用
- Thank you. - No problem.
我可以骑车送你回家吗
Can I spin you home?
我不知道你还有车
I didn't know you had a car.
那么你住在哪儿
So where d'you live?
离学校不远 哈考特梯田那边
Not far from the school. Harcourt Terrace.
噢 运河边上
Ah, by the canal.
你在那儿长大吗
Did you grow up there?
对 虽然我家很可能要搬走了
Yeah. Though we're probably moving.
我父母破产了
My parents are broke.
那就是他们送去这间学校的原因
That's why they sent me to that school.
对 我之前还疑惑来着
Yeah, I was wondering about that.
那些人中就数你比较时髦
You're a bit posh for around there.
说说你自己吧 你家的房子可真大
Speak for yourself. Your house is massive.
是吗
Is it?
我父母可能要离婚
My parents are probably splitting up.
这可真悲伤 你还好吗
That's sad. Are you doing okay with it?
嗯 还好
Oh, yeah.
在他们中间会让我有点紧张
It's a bit intense being around them.
天啊 演电视剧一样
Jesus, all that drama.
我很庆幸我没有父母
I'm glad I don't have parents.
我们之前来过这个广场吗
Haven't we been down this square already?
额 没有
Uh, no.
你是我见过的人里骑车最慢的
You are the slowest cyclist I have ever met.
好吧
Okay.
谢谢
Thanks.
今天玩得很开心 没错 真的很开心
- That was great fun. - Yeah, it was really fun.
嘿宝贝
Hey, baby!
Hi.
这是伊万亚当
- This is Evan Adams. - Word.
你好吗 这是我之前和你提过
- How do you do? - This is the singer
那个乐队的主唱
in the band I was telling you about.
哦 是吗 她给我放过你们的歌
Oh, yeah, she played me your song.
氛围不错
Good vibes.
有点Duran Duran的风格 还有一点新式的浪漫
Little bit of Duran Duran in there, bit of New Romance.
是什么风格来着
What style would you say you were?
我是个未来主义者
I'm a futurist.
史诗般的
Epic.
那么我们未来见
See you in the future, then.
好了吗 宝贝 嗯
- Ready, baby? - Yeah.
好的 我们下次再见
- Okay. - I'll see you soon.
再见
See you.
我们下次再录新的录像
Let's make another video sometime.
领结不错
Nice blouse!
噢 该死的
Aw, shit.
你得想象这并不是
You have to imagine it's not as...
垃圾
Shit?
这个会变好的
This will be good.
真的吗 没错
- Really? - Yeah.
你只是需要台好的摄像机和一位好导演
You just need some proper cameras and a good director.
只要你在脑海中构思好了 这是最重要的
But as long as it's in your head, that's what counts.
这是锻炼你的想象力
It's an exercise in imagination.
思维再开阔点 康纳 这只是达到目的的一种手段
Think big, Conor. This is just a means to an end.
她看起来美极了
And she looks amazing.
她得出现在所有的录像里
She's got to be in all the videos.
真的吗 噢 没错
- Yeah? - Oh, yeah.
她是世界级的
She's world-class.
没有了她 你们就是巷道里的一群基佬
Without her, you're just a bunch of gay-looking kids down an alleyway.
你有没有亲过她
Have you kissed her yet?
没有 为什么不
- No way. - Why not?
她比我大一岁
She's a year older than me.
还有 她已经有了男朋友
And, anyway, she's got a boyfriend.
噢 谁啊 伊万亚当
- Ah. Who? - Evan Adams.
是个成熟的男人
He's, like, a full-grown man.
他有车 什么都有
He's got a car and all and stubble.
他为什么要跟个小女孩约会
What's he doing hanging out with a kid?
她并不真的像个孩子
She's not really like a kid.
Hmm.
这是什么 家庭作业
- What's this? - Homework.
你已经很棒了 可以变得更好
You're good. Get better.
不过你是怎么知道他是她男朋友的
How d'you know he's her boyfriend anyway?
看起来像是
It seemed like it.
她拉开他的车门 音乐声震天
Pulled off in his car, music blaring.
他真的很酷
He's pretty cool.
他平时听些什么
What was he listening to?
创世纪乐团
Genesis.
他不是个问题
He will not be a problem.
真的吗 相信我
- Really? - Trust me.
不会有女人会真的爱上听菲尔·柯林斯的男人
No woman can truly love a man who listens to Phil Collins.
Shh.
Listen.
我觉得她有外遇了
I think she's having an affair.
什么 为什么
What? Why?
她每星期都有几次坐上司的顺风车回家
She gets a lift home from her boss a couple of times a week.
她不开车 这有什么问题吗
She doesn't drive. What's wrong with that?
她到了离家100码的地方就会下车
She gets out of the car about 100 yards away from the house.
是个值得紧张的事
It's a nervous thing.
做的有点过头了
She's overcompensating.
晚安
Good night, then.
嘿 康纳 怎么了
Hey, Conor, what's going on?
我不知道
I don't know.
你在干什么呢
What are you doing?
只是 在忙兔子的事
Just, just rabbit stuff.
你想不想写首新歌
D'you want to write a new song?
嗯 我想
Yes, I do.
唱片
Records.
很棒的唱片
Really good records.
我哥哥喜欢这个
My brother loves this.
他说这是家庭作业
He says it's homework.
你知道低音电吉他和低音踏板是如何弹出同样的节奏吗
You see how bass guitar and the bass pedal are playing the same rhythm?
你现在就能听到 等等
You'll hear it now, wait.
我跟你们说过多少次 尤其是你 永远都在床上拉屎
I told all of yous, you especially, shitting on the bed all the time.
你不能把兔子放在床上 又期望它们不在你的床上拉屎
You can't put rabbits on the bed and not expect them to shit on your bed.
和弦 像这样
A chord like...
没错
Yeah.
在这个地方
Somewhere in the...
♪ Da, da, da, da, da, miles ♪
♪ Miles below me ♪ So...
♪ Up to the stars she shows me ♪
♪ Dame Street, George's Street ♪
♪ Miles below me... ♪
感觉很棒 我喜欢这个
- That's good. I like that. - Yeah.
A调不错
I love that middle A.
嗯 去拿吉他 我们来试试
Yeah, go get the guitar; let's try it out.
木吉他更好听
It-it'll sound better on the acoustic.
大伙儿一起 听起来会很好听
It's gonna sound great with the lads.
♪ It's 2:00 on the edge of the morning ♪
♪ She's running magical circles around my head ♪
♪ I hitch a ride on a dream she's driving ♪
♪ She turns to kiss me, I crash back into bed ♪
♪ Across the street on a grayed out Monday ♪
♪ I see the girl with the eyes I can't describe ♪
♪ And suddenly it's a perfect Sunday ♪
♪ And everything is more real than life ♪
♪ I think I'm back in the dream ♪
♪ I think I'm back on the ceiling ♪
♪ It's such a beautiful feeling ♪
♪ Going up ♪
♪ She lights me up ♪
♪ She breaks me up ♪
♪ She lifts me up ♪
♪ You find a mystery bound in perfection ♪
♪ You've got to read, but you don't wanna reach the end ♪
♪ 'Cause what if everything beautiful's fiction ♪
♪ And this reality's just pretend? ♪
♪ And then I'm back in the dream ♪
♪ Looking up at the ceiling ♪
♪ It's such a beautiful feeling ♪
♪ Going up ♪
♪ She lights me up ♪
♪ She breaks me up ♪
♪ She lifts me up ♪
♪ Up to the stars she shows me ♪
♪ Dame Street, George's Street ♪
♪ Miles below me ♪
♪ Up where the world won't let us down ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na ♪
♪ Going up ♪
♪ She lights me up ♪
♪ She breaks me up ♪
♪ She lifts me up. ♪
大家快看 大卫鲍伊
Boys, look at David Bowie.
我喜欢这个
Oh, I like this.
这是什么 我的乐队
- What is it? - My band.
你有乐队？厉害 对
- You're in a band? Cool. - Yeah.
乐队叫什么名字
What are they called?
唱街
Sing Street.
这是谁 你女朋友吗
Who's this now? Your girlfriend?
Yeah.
不是
No.
她是我的朋友
She's a friend of mine.
她是个模特 嗯
- She's a model. - Hmm.
但她已经有男朋友了
But she's got a boyfriend.
一个年长的人
An older guy.
Ah.
复杂的少男少女们
All the complicated boys and girls.
干的不错
Good work.
贝克斯特 要见康纳·劳乐
Brother Baxter would like to see, uh, Conor Lawlor.
嗯 康纳
Okay. Conor.
康纳·劳乐
Conor Lawlor.
发生什么事
What's going on?
您指什么
With what?
This.
好吧
Oh, well.
我检查过规则手册
I checked the rule book...
你提到棕色皮鞋的那条
the-the one you mentioned about brown shoes...
我找不到有关化妆或者改变发色的规定
and I couldn't find anything about makeup or altering hair color.
噢 还有外表
Oh, and look.
我在画室用颜料画的
I painted these with paint from the art room.
现在给我去厕所把妆都洗掉
Head down to the toilet and remove the makeup right now.
为什么 我让你去
- Why? - Because I told you to.
但我加入乐队了
But I'm in a band.
这是支学校的乐队 而且我认为我们的外表很重要
It's a school band, and I think it's important that we have a look.
你是个男人 男人从来不会化妆
You're a man. Men don't wear makeup.
可为什么不呢
But why not?
18世纪的人都会化妆
People in the 18th century wore makeup.
这意味着像莫扎特那样的人也会化妆 而他也是个男人
That means people like Mozart wore makeup, and he was a man.
所以你现在是莫扎特了 是吗
So you're Mozart now, are you?
我就变成萨列里了 是吗
That makes me Salieri, is it?
萨列里是谁
Who's Salieri?
你有一张清秀的脸
You've a fine face.
不用化妆也足够好看
Pretty enough without makeup.
把它洗掉吧
Take it off.
你可以用我的盟洗室 如果你想的话
You can use my bathroom, if you like.
到我这儿来
Come on in here.
我现在要回教室了
I'm gonna go to class now.
天哪
Jesus!
你不能这么做
You can't do this!
你想打个赌吗
Do you want to bet?
我会帮你洗干净的 别担心
I'll get you clean, don't worry.
洗的干干净净
Clean you all up.
把你身上这些乱七八糟的洗掉
Get all that shite off you.
为你天生的优点自豪吧
Take pride in your God-given features.
别再搞这些华丽摇滚了
No more Ziggy Stardust.
嘿 科兹莫 谁
- Hey, Cosmo. - Who?
科兹莫 我现在这么叫你
Cosmo. That's what I'm calling you now.
如果你想在乐队里 你得有一个好听的名字
You're gonna need a catchy name if you're gonna be in a band.
没错
Right.
发生什么事了
What happened?
什么也没有
Nothing.
过来
Come on.
我真的很喜欢你的歌
I really liked your song.
它让我哭了
It made me cry.
Oh.
我真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
不这是件好事
No, that's a good thing.
那天坐在车上的男人是谁
So who's the guy with the car?
伊万吗？
Evan?
对
Yeah.
他是你的男朋友吗
Is he your boyfriend?
我们分分合合
We're on and off.
这很复杂
It's complicated.
事实上我们现在打算分开一段时间
We're actually on a little break at the moment.
这样
Yeah.
好主意
Good idea.
分开一年或更久
Take a break for a year or so.
再做出理智的选择
Get some perspective.
实际上他真的是个很好的人
He's actually a really nice guy.
没错
Yeah.
虽然在音乐上没什么品位
Shit taste in music, though.
不久以后我们要去伦敦了
We're going to London soon.
我年纪不够一个人去不了 他打点好了所有事
I'm too young to go on my own, so he's organized everything.
伊万有什么好的
What's in it for Evan?
你在妒忌吗 科兹莫
Are you jealous, Cosmo?
我为什么要妒忌他
Why would I be jealous?
没错
Exactly.
你有空会给我写首欢乐的歌吗
Will you write me a happy song sometime?
我需要笑容
I need a laugh.
但如果我不觉得快乐呢
But what if I don't feel happy?
你的问题是你并不为你的悲伤而快乐
Your problem is that you're not happy being sad.
那就是爱的感觉 科兹莫
But that's what love is, Cosmo.
悲喜交加
Happy-sad.
该死的 我等会得先走
Shit, I've got to go soon.
我们只有半个小时在屋子里吃晚饭
We only have a half hour dinner window in our house.
房子什么样 你住哪里
So, what's the house like, where you live?
房子很不错
It's nice.
比我之前住过的一些地方好很多
Nicer than some of the dumps I've lived in.
你的父母在哪里
So where are your parents?
我爸爸去世很久了
My dad's brown bread.
他出了车祸
He got hit by a car.
哦 上帝 很抱歉
Oh, my God. Sorry.
没关系
Really don't be.
他是个酒鬼 他活该
He was a drunk. He deserved it.
我妈妈频繁进出医院
And me ma's in and out of hospital.
为什么
Why?
她是个护士
She's a nurse.
哦 好吧
Oh, right.
不 她是燥狂抑郁病患者
No, she's manic-depressive.
真是有点 悲喜交加
So, like, happy-sad.
你真有趣 我喜欢那点
You're funny, I like that.
在我走之前 还要拍录像的话记得告诉我
Well, let me know if you need me for any more videos before I go.
你什么时候走
When are you going?
很快了
Soon.
她那样说是什么意思
What did she mean by that?
她的意思是 你要取得一定成绩
Well, I think what she means is that you need to reach a place in your life
那样你可以顺利面对悲伤
where you're okay with your sadness.
这是很抽象的东西
It's pretty high concept stuff.
她说她多大来着？
How old d'you say she was again?
十六岁
Sixteen.
简直就是出家了
It's monastic.
就像一个和尚
She's like a monk.
听起来 她很自命不凡
She sounds really pretentious.
为什么就因为她想退学从事自己的职业吗
Why, 'cause she wants to leave school and follow her vocation?
你觉得成为模特是一种职业吗
You call wanting to be a model a vocation?
安 什么都可以成为职业
Anything can be a vocation, Ann.
出租车司机 清洁工 诗人
Being a taxi driver, being a bin man, being a poet,
歌手 画家
being a singer, being an artist.
布兰登 我从未想过成为一名画家
Brendan, I never wanted to be an artist.
在你小时候 你手不离画笔
We couldn't get the brush out of your hand when you were a kid.
做建筑师怎么了
What is wrong with being an architect?
这不是一种职业
It's not a vocation.
我觉得每件事都是一种职业
I thought everything was a vocation.
安 不要和我玩文字游戏
Don't be playing word games with me, Ann.
我不玩文字 好吗
I don't do "words," all right?
康纳 来吧
Come on, Conor.
安 睡觉之前把灯关上
Turn out the lights before you go to bed, Ann.
她父亲去世了 母亲是个精神病
So her dad's dead and her mam is a lunatic.
你还觉得你有问题
And you thought you had problems.
我现在知道年长男朋友是怎么一回事了
I see now what the older boyfriend thing is about.
恋父情结
Daddy issues.
我以前也认识这种小妞儿
I used to know chicks like this.
它们很棘手 需要保护
They're tricky, and they need a lot of protecting.
康纳 你有把握吗
Are you up to that, Conor?
我不知道
I don't know.
那这些都是为了啥
So what's it all about?
我觉得她是一个完美的人类
I think she's just an amazing human being.
我从来没见过这样的人
I've never seen anyone like her.
她说话的方式和外貌
The way she talks and looks.
她戴着太阳眼镜 取下来的时候 她的眼睛
She wears these sunglasses, and when she takes them off, her eyes
就像穿越月球的云朵
are like the clouds clearing past the moon.
有时候 我很希望只看到她
Sometimes I just want to cry looking at her.
这些才是“悲喜交加”
They're happy-sad.
“悲喜交加”是什么意思
So how do you mean you're "happy-sad"?
对啊 我怎么卖这个呢
Yeah, how am I supposed to market that?
我们不在流行了
It means we're not pop anymore.
我们流行过吗
We were pop?
听着对我来说 什么都可以
Listen, I'm happy being anything.
我只想做音乐
I just want to play music.
可以
That's fine.
埃蒙 做你自己
Be who you are, Eamon.
我不知道我是谁
Well, I don't know who I am.
可能我也“悲喜交加”
Maybe I'm happy-sad, too.
我不知道
I don't know.
“悲喜交加”的意思是什么
What does happy-sad even mean?
怎么可能同时具备 这不合常理
How can we be both things? It makes no sense.
意思是 我现在困住这个鬼地方
It means that I'm stuck in this shithole
整天要跟一些蠢蛋 强奸犯 暴力狂周旋
full of morons and rapists and bullies, and I'm gonna deal with it, okay?
这就是生活啊
It's just how life is.
我会试着接受它 处理好它
I'm gonna try and accept it and get on with it
创作出一些艺术
and make some art.
那是怎么影响我们的音乐的
So how does that affect our music?
有积极影响 好吧
- Positively. - All right.
好的
Okay.
这个录像是关于一个男人站在码头的路中央
So the idea of this video is about a guy standing halfway down a pier,
一个漂亮的女人路过他 走向了灯塔
and a beautiful woman walks past him towards the lighthouse.
一个半小时之后 她还没有回来
Half an hour later, she hasn't come back.
他去看 发现她消失了
So he investigates, but she's gone.
啥？
What?
她自杀了
She killed herself.
不 她是美人鱼 她跳回海里了
No, she's a mermaid, and she's jumped back into the sea.
渔网把她捞了到城里面 奄奄一息
You see, she got washed up in a fishing net so she's been in the city, and she's been dying
但她很想回到水里 回到她朋友身边
to get back to the water, to her friends.
回到属于她的地方
Back to where she belongs.
这样 好多了
That's much better.
我知道
I know.
我们在这里演奏 拉菲从那走过
Okay, so we're playing here and Raphina walks by.
我从哪里跳呢 这里
- So where do I jump from? - Here.
啊 好的
- Aah! - Yeah.
看起来怎么样 伙伴们
How'd that look, lads?
看起来不错
Yeah, it looked all right.
蠢死了
It's a bit shit.
看起来应该像要跳进去之类的
That supposed to look like they're jumping in or something?
好的
Yeah.
看起来不像
It doesn't.
相信我 会奏效的
Trust me. It'll work.
♪ Fake deals in the supermarket ♪
♪ TVs selling what you can't get ♪
♪ She laughs, "Nowhere is as pretty as this" ♪
♪ Gray cars crawlin' in the slow lane ♪
♪ Lost stars waiting for the DART train ♪
♪ She smiles, turns and blows the city a kiss ♪
♪ Under the waves I feel her ♪
♪ Pull my body down... ♪
我去
- Shit. - ♪ Under the waves ♪
拉菲那 怎么了
- What the hell, Raphina? - ♪ She takes me... ♪
继续拍摄 救救我
Keep bloody filming! Save me!
我不会游泳
I can't swim!
♪ I can be miles away ♪
♪ She calls to me ♪
♪ This girl is a beautiful sea ♪
♪ The girl is a beautiful sea. ♪
-你在想什么呢 -拍到了吗？
- What were you thinking? - Did you get it?
嗯 蛮不错的
Yeah, it was great!
棒极了
Ah! Fantastic!
你真的不会游泳吗
Can you really not swim?
不会
No.
那你为什么那样做
So why'd you do that, then?
科兹莫 为了艺术
For our art, Cosmo.
做事不能只做一半
You can never do anything by half.
你懂了吗
Do you understand that?
很抱歉
I'm... I'm sorry.
听着 我有点
Look, I was...
非常不错
Great is what it was.
干的不错
Fair play.
伊万怎么办
What about Evan?
美好的气氛被你破坏了
Yeah, you ruined it.
天气好的时候 可以清楚看到英国的岛屿
You know, on a clear day, you can actually see the mainland of Britain.
离威尔士海岸仅30英里
Island's only 30 miles from the coast of Wales.
我打赌 你不知道
Bet you didn't know that.
雨刚停的时候 空气里没有灰尘
It has to have just rained, no dust in the air.
你就可以看见
You can just about see it.
不会吧
No way.
你怎么知道这样的事儿
How do you know stuff like that?
我祖父在去霍利黑德的船上工作
My granddad worked on the ships to Holyhead.
他常带我来这
He used to take me out here.
我们经常乘他的小船出海捕鱼
We used to go out in his little boat, fishing.
哇
Wow.
所以我回伦敦以后可以向你挥手
So I can wave back to you when I'm in London.
我哥告诉我 伟大的艺术家都得离开这座岛
My brother says all the great artists had to get off this island.
留下的都抑郁了 成了酒鬼
The ones who stayed got depressed and turned into alcoholics.
有道理
Makes sense.
你经常提起你哥
You talk about your brother a lot.
你真的爱他吗
Do you really love him?
他小的时候 本来要去德国
He was gonna go to Germany when he was younger.
但在他毕业之前 父母不可能让他走
But my parents would never let him go without finishing school.
他想逃跑 他计划好所有事儿
He was gonna run away; he had the whole thing planned, so he says.
接下来呢
So what happened?
妈妈发现了
My mum found out.
她让这个计划夭折了
She closed it down.
她不想他走
She didn't want him to go.
可能她太爱他了
Maybe she loved him too much.
是的
Yeah.
我觉得你蛮对的
Actually, I think you're right.
我爸爸以前就是经常这样说
That's what my dad always used to say.
妈妈去医院时
When my ma would be in hospital, in a spell,
就剩我和他了
and it was just the two of us.
我打扮的漂漂亮亮的 约朋友出去玩
So I'd get all dressed up to go out with my friends,
他叫我留在家里
then he'd make me stay in.
之后
And afterwards, he'd say,
我很爱你 就是这样
"I love you too much, is all."
事实上 妈妈比我漂亮多了
And the thing is, me ma's much better-looking than I am,
我真不知道他为什么老烦我
so I don't really know why he'd bother with me.
真是奇怪的爱 是吗
It's a strange kind of love, isn't it?
父母的爱
Parents.
我可以救她的
I would've saved her.
但我没有
And I could've.
-不 你救不了她 -我可以救的
- No, you couldn't have. - I could've.
-你太小了 -我不小
- You're too small. - I'm not too small.
你们都太渺小了
You're way too small.
我给你们讲个笑话
I've a good joke for you guys.
逼逼 知道是什么吗
Vagina. Do you get it?
-不知道 -你还是太年轻
- No. - Exactly.
好
All right, uh...
为什么粉红…
why did the pink...
看她
Look at her.
她迅速跑回家 只是为了最后一点余晖
She races home every evening just to catch that last little bit of sun...
点支烟 读读她的文章
...have a cigarette and read her papers.
她总想去西班牙度假
She's always talking about going on a holiday to Spain.
但他从未带她去过
But he never takes her.
这就是她得到的
That's all she gets.
太阳到树后面去 她就进来了
Then that tall tree blocks it, and she comes in.
我常在想 她在想什么
I often wonder what she's thinking about.
太美妙了
That's amazing.
乐队怎么样了
Ah, how's the band getting along?
这次又叫什么
What are they called again?
怪人吗
"The Queers"?
巴里 这名字不错
Good one, Barry.
有人记下来了吗
Is, uh, anyone getting these down?
巴里 你知道你像谁吗
You know who you're a bit like, Barry?
奥斯卡 王尔德
Uh, Oscar Wilde.
他去了哪个班
What class is he in, then?
巴里 他不是学校里的 笨蛋
He's not in school, Barry, you spanner.
总有一天我要杀了你
You know I am gonna kill you one of these days.
你不会的
No, you're not.
因为你没有存在过 什么
- 'Cause you don't even exist. - What?
可能你活在我的世界 我却没有活在你的世界
Maybe you're living in my world; I'm not living in yours.
你只是我的歌曲的素材
You're just material for my songs.
你得小心接下来和我说的话了
Man, I'd be very careful about what you say to me next.
巴里 放倒他
Floor him, Barry.
我不想又和你打架
I don't want to have to batter you again.
来吧 巴里
Go ahead, Barry.
来啊
Go on.
你只会摧毁
You only have the power to stop things.
不会创造
But not to create.
学校舞厅学期末舞会
"End of term disco at the school hall.
DJ和灯光 意思是？
DJ and lights." So?
意思是我们能不能在那里演出 第一次演出
I say we ask if we can play there. First gig.
-我们还没准备好 -我们可以的
- We're not ready. - We could be.
定个目标 准备一下
We need a deadline, something to prepare for.
还有考试 要准备考试
We have exams. We need to prepare for them.
期中考试而已 无关紧要
Yeah, they're midterm exams. They don't mean anything.
对我妈妈有意义 她希望我可以上大学
Yeah, well, they do to my ma. She wants me to go to college.
拿到毕业证之类的
Get qualifications and all.
舞会有女孩子吗
Will there be girls at the disco?
-有啊 -那就去演
Yes. I say we do it.
我们有5首歌
We have five songs.
要准备一个半小时演出 所以还要三首
We'd need a half-hour set, so three more.
♪ Who the hell are you ♪
♪ To tell me what to do ♪
♪ You wear a dress ♪
♪ And tell me not to wear brown shoes ♪
♪ Do you think you... ♪
你去哪里
Come on, where are you going?
现在是晚上九点半
It's half-9:00 at night.
为什么你突然装作你关心一切的样子
Why are you acting, all of a sudden, - as if it matters? - Come on,
-胡扯 -好像你在意一样
- this is bullshit. - As if you care?
你去街上 十分钟以后回来
You're gonna go down the street. You're gonna be back in ten minutes.
-这次不行 -你一直这么说
- Not this time. - That's what you always say.
这不是我一直说的
It is not what I always say!
-都晚上九点了外边很黑 -我有去的地方
It's 9:00 at night! It's dark! I've got somewhere to go to.
你不准开车走 我想不知名先生会开车过来
You're not taking the car. I suppose Mr. What's-His-Name will come around in his.
-他叫托尼 -托尼会开车过来
- His name's Tony. - Tony can come around with his.
这条裙子怎么样 穿这条吧
Look here, what about this dress? This dress is lovely. Do you want to take that one?
-别碰我的东西 -你穿这个看着很性感
Don't touch my things! You'd look pretty sexy in that one.
你何曾关心过我穿什么
When was the last time you noticed anything I wore, any way that I looked?
这个蛮性感的 他会喜欢的 是吧
That's a pretty sexy one, isn't it? He'll love that one, won't he?
内裤呢 带内裤了吗？
What about knickers? Have you got knickers?
你可能不要穿吧 放一边去
You probably don't... you don't need any knickers, do you? Just put them away!
康纳 这就是生活
This is life, Conor.
像开着偷来的车
Drive it like you stole it.
来吧
Come on!
才不
No!
快点让她起来 让她起来
- Come on, get her up. - Let's get her up!
你在做什么
What do you think you're doing?
这很不错
That's great!
拉里 试一下踩坺
Try a bit of hi-hat, Larry.
♪ You just can't stand the way ♪
♪ That I walked out from the wreckage ♪
♪ Can't understand the way that I turned myself around ♪
♪ I tried to terminate this war ♪
♪ With you ♪
♪ But you won't let it go ♪
♪ You keep coming back for more... ♪
开始
And begin.
这是什么意思
What does this even mean?
吃我蛋蛋吧
Suck my balls.
-别说话 -晚安了
- Quiet! - Night now.
嘿 嗨
- Hey. - Hi.
你想来一次探险吗
Do you want to go on an adventure?
可以
Oh. Okay.
看见那里的杆子了吗 黄的那个
Do you see the pole there, the yellow one?
看见了
Yeah.
我们要去那里
That's where we're heading.
我爸妈要是知道把船开走了 会杀了我的
If my parents found out I took this out, they'd kill me.
你以前开过吗
Have you taken it out before?
几周前开过
Every few weeks.
船就像乐器 得经常用才好
A boat's like a musical instrument... it doesn't like it if you don't use it.
我祖父这样说的 我得替他照看它
That's what my granddad said, you know, so I like to look after it for him.
有一艘到英格兰的船
Look, there's the ferry heading to England.
装满了爱尔兰人
Full of lrish people.
好的 走吧
Okay, so go.
你不能阻止我们从残骸中走出来
"You just can't stand the way that we walked out from the wreckage."
什么残骸
What wreckage?
家庭的残骸
Maybe the wreckage of family.
我刚才在想这些
That's what I was thinking about.
好的 下一个
Okay, next.
你不能阻止我改变生活
"You just can't stand the way that I turned my life around."
这和你有关系
That's about you.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我在想我的爸妈和我的麻烦
Well, I was thinking about my parents and how I thought I had problems.
还有你改变生活的方式
And the way you've turned your life around.
我改变我的生活了吗
How have I turned my life around?
看看你 你要去一个新的国家了
Well, look at you. You're going to a new country.
你有工作了 你看起来棒极了
You've got a vocation. You look amazing.
停下了 停什么
Stop. Stop what?
处理这些歌吧 这个录像关于什么的
Just get on with the song. What's the video gonna be about?
这是在学校毕业舞会拍的 像是在美国的高中
So... I think it's set at a school prom, like in an American high school.
我一直希望能去美国学校念书
I've always wanted to go to an American school.
有很多女孩子和发胶
With girls and hair gel.
你看过《回到未来》吗
Have you seen "Back to the Future"?
我看过所有的电影
I see all the films.
想象有个乐队 都穿着西装
Imagine the band, all in suits.
我脑袋里有所有场景
I have all the shots planned in my head.
我哥告诉我 要敢想
My brother told me to think big.
我穿着50年代的裙子
And what if I come in a big '50s dress?
好的
Yeah.
所有人都分开了消失了
And the whole crowd parts and everyone disappears.
然后我们进入这个大舞会
And then we all break out into this big dance routine,
所有人都在那里
and everyone is there.
我和你跑入夜色中
And then you and I just run off into the night
身后是城市的灯火
with the twinkling lights of the city behind us.
之前你还挺迷人的？
You were a bit attractive back there.
之前？
Back where?
船上
On the boat.
谢谢你
Thank you.
一点点
Just a little bit.
像个船长
Bit like a captain.
我喜欢那种感觉
I like that.
哎哎
Aye-aye.
你总是那么迷人
You're always very attractive.
我知道
I know.
很自负
And very conceited.
别说了
Just stop talking.
这一次
For once.
我只是有点
I've just...
抱歉
Sorry.
-现在 怎么 -好的
- Now, is it...? - Oh, yeah.
好的
Yeah.
我们什么时候拍录像
So when are we shooting this video?
下周六
Saturday next.
哦
Oh.
康纳
Conor?
不错 起床了
Good. You're up.
我可以解释
I can explain, see...
康纳 这和你的考试没有关系
It's not about your exams, Conor.
坐下 我们要和你们谈谈
We need to talk to all of you. Sit down.
首先 我们不想做什么大交易
Well, so, firstly, we don't want to make a big deal about this, you know.
我们考虑了很久了
It's something we've thought about a lot.
很多已婚的伴侣
A lot of married couples...
你的父亲和我分开了
Your father and I are splitting up.
谢谢你 很不错
Thank you. That's great.
这是时间问题
It was just a matter of time.
我去打包东西
I'll go get the bags packed.
你准备好了的时候 告诉我
Let me know when we're ready to go.
你怎么不坐下 布兰顿就一会
Why don't you sit down, Brendan, for a second?
我们会告诉你我们得想法
We'll tell you what we're thinking.
你在看你是不是同意
You see if you agree.
共识吗
A consensus?
蛮有新意的
That's novel. Okay.
你的妈妈爱上了托尼
Your mother has fallen in love with Tony.
之后不久他们就搬进了他的公寓
They're gonna be moving into his apartment for awhile and...
是的
Yeah.
这个房子有人要买
We've had an offer on this house.
价钱只值房子的一半 但是我们也卖
It's half what it's worth, but we're gonna take it.
这么大的房子靠我一个人负担不了
I can't afford to live here on my own.
你们是要离婚
So you're getting a divorce?
在爱尔兰不能离婚 我们只是合法分居
Can't get divorced in lreland, so we'll be legally separated.
我要去找一个公寓 你们三会住在那里
I'm gonna be getting an apartment, and you three will live between there and...
和那
there.
我不会待在托尼家的
I'm not gonna be staying at Tony's.
把话说明白了
Let's get that crystal clear.
我宁愿睡在街上
I'd rather sleep on the street.
布兰顿 我知道你有点失望
I understand this is upsetting for you, Brendan.
你什么都不知道
You don't understand anything!
你们所有人
For all of you.
这是胡扯
This is bullshit.
你是对的
So you were right.
他们也是人 我早就告诉过你了
They're just human beings. I told you that.
我还希望他们这个月底来看我演出呢
I was sort of hoping they'd come to my gig at the end of the month.
你觉得他们会改变吗
What, you thought they'd just become different people
会知道你在做什么 和你要什么吗
and start noticing what you were doing and what you wanted?
他们有自己的事儿要处理 他们不会去看你那愚蠢的演出
They've got their own shit going on. They're not going to your stupid gig.
怎么愚蠢了
So why is it stupid now?
不是蠢 是很恼人
It's not that it's stupid, it's just annoying.
-你怎么了 -不知道 我正在戒药
What's wrong with you? I don't know. I'm in withdrawal!
-戒什么？ -康纳 我两天都没有吸过了
- From what? - I haven't smoked hash - in two days, Conor.
-为什么？ -为了在人生里干些有意义的事
- Why? - So I can do something with my life.
例如
Like what?
你看见那把吉他了吗
Do you see that guitar?
我以前吉他弹得 很好
I used to be able to play that guitar... well.
我以前有不少靓妹
I used to ride hot girls.
我200米比谁都跑得快
I could run 200 meters faster than anybody in my school.
你是最小的
You're the youngest.
你跟着我走的路
You get to follow the path that I macheted
来到这糟心的家里
through the jungle that is our mad family.
我和他们待了6年
I was alone with them for six years.
你觉得现在他们疯了是吧
You think they're crazy now?
想想他们20多岁的样子
Think about what they were like when they were in their late 20s.
两个天主教徒和一个小孩住在一个出租屋里
Two Catholics in a rented flat with a screaming baby,
为了做爱而结婚
who just got married because they wanted to have sex.
他们甚至不爱对方
They didn't even love each other.
我就在他们中间 独自一人
I was in the middle of that, alone.
然后你们出生了
And then you came along.
谢谢上帝
Thank God!
你追随了
And you followed...
我选的路
the path that I cut for us.
我没完成的
Untouched.
你游进了我的急流
You just moved in my jet stream.
康纳 人们在笑话我
And people laugh at me, Conor.
瘾君子 退学的人
The stoner, the college dropout.
他们却赞扬你 这很好
And they praise you, which is fine!
但是曾经
But once...
我是一个喷射发动机
I was a fucking jet engine!
马上回来
Back in a second.
得去浴室洗洗
Need to go to the bathroom.
兄台
Ngig.
-你能搬一下那个话筒吗 -你在期待她吗
Can you move that mic stand over - a bit more, all right? - Are you expecting her soon?
我觉得她要来了 但是不知道她在哪
I thought she was coming, but I don't know where she is.
你最好拍点什么回来 你还要一个小时时间
Right, so you better get something filmed. Yous have an hour.
康纳 快来 她不来了
Come on, Conor. She's not coming.
随便做点什么 好吗
Let's just do whatever. Okay.
伙计们 过来
Come over, guys.
这是一个学校录像 但不是爱尔兰的学校
Okay, so this is like a school video, except not like an lrish school,
更像是美国的学校 是个舞会
more like an American school, and it's prom night.
你看过《回到未来》吗
Have you seen "Back to the Future"?
就像是50年代的舞蹈
Okay, well, it's just kind of like '50s dancing, and...
像什么
Like what?
就像来自50年代的东西 弹个响指…
It's... like dancing from the '50s, you know, clicking fingers and...
我们现在能试一下吗
Can we try some now, actually? Just...
可以 可以
Yeah. Yeah.
就这样 可以
That's it. Yeah.
可以再转一下或者怎么样
Yeah, maybe do a few twirls and stuff.
自然点就好
Just do what's natural.
尽可能的自然
Make it as natural as possible.
开始放歌吧
Let's get some playback.
♪ You just can't stand the way ♪
♪ That I walked out from the wreckage ♪
♪ Can't understand the way ♪
♪ That I turned myself around ♪
♪ I tried to terminate this war ♪
♪ With you ♪
♪ But you won't let it go ♪
♪ You keep coming back for more ♪
♪ Freedom, I'm takin' it back ♪
♪ I'm outta here, no turnin' back ♪
♪ In a baby blue Cadillac ♪
♪ Just when I was stallin' ♪
♪ I heard an angel callin' ♪
♪ This is your life ♪
♪ You can go anywhere ♪
♪ You gotta grab the wheel and own it ♪
♪ And drive it like you stole it ♪
♪ Roll it, this is your life ♪
♪ You can be anything ♪
♪ You gotta learn to rock and roll it ♪
♪ You gotta put the pedal down ♪
♪ And drive it like you stole it ♪
♪ We get stuck in the dirt ♪
♪ And we can't see where we're goin' ♪
♪ We face all kinds of hurt ♪
♪ And the friction slows us down ♪
♪ But I won't be waiting here ♪
♪ For the world to win me gold ♪
♪ I'll leave your dust behind me ♪
♪ Stranded in the road ♪
♪ Freedom ♪
♪ I'm takin' it back ♪
♪ Attitude ♪
♪ I'm givin' it back ♪
♪ In a baby blue Cadillac ♪
♪ Just when I was stallin' ♪
♪ I heard an angel callin' ♪
♪ This is your life ♪
♪ You can go anywhere ♪
♪ You gotta grab the wheel and own it ♪
♪ You gotta put the pedal down ♪
♪ And drive it like you stole it ♪
♪ This is your life ♪
♪ You can go anywhere ♪
♪ You gotta grab the wheel and own it ♪
♪ And drive it like you stole it ♪
♪ Roll it, this is your life ♪
♪ You can be anything ♪
♪ You gotta learn to rock and roll it ♪
♪ You gotta put the pedal down ♪
♪ And drive it like you stole it ♪
♪ Hoo, hoo, hoo-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ Hoo, hoo, hoo-ooh-ooh. ♪
Um...
就这样 拍吧
All right, let's shoot it.
好 怎么了
- Oh. - Yeah?
嗨 拉菲娜在这里吗
Hi. Is Raphina there?
她不住这里了
No. She doesn't live here anymore.
她在哪了 我不知道
- Wh-Where is she? - I don't know.
你是乐队那家伙吗
Are you the bloke in the band?
是的
Yeah.
我为了你输钱了
I lost money on you.
什么
What?
我们都在打赌
Yeah, we all... had bets going.
觉得你会赢
Thought you were gonna win.
她要去做她自己的事儿 是吗
Look, she was always gonna do her own thing, wasn't she?
她对那个很疯狂 很坚定
She's mad like that, determined.
她在哪了
Where is she?
和她朋友去伦敦了 就在昨晚
She's gone to London with her fella. Last night.
哇
Wow, um...
她给我留了消息吗
Did she leave any message for me or anything?
没有
No.
好吧
All right. No, uh...
还算不错
That's cool, yeah.
你的歌不错
Your songs are good.
谢谢夸奖
Thanks.
抓住这里
Hold on to that nice and tight there.
这是71英寸
That's... 71 inches.
♪ And I'm back in the dream ♪
♪ Think I'm back on the ceiling ♪
♪ Goin' up ♪
♪ She lights me up ♪
♪ She breaks me up ♪
♪ She lifts me ♪
♪ Up ♪
♪ Goin' up ♪
♪ She lights me up... ♪
-拉菲娜吗 -不 抱歉
-Raphina? -No, sorry.
-嘿 等一下 -怎么了
- Hey, wait. - What?
拉菲娜
Raphina.
谁 拉菲娜
Who? Raphina.
哦 我是拉菲娜的妹妹 不好意思
Oh, no, I'm Raphina's younger sister. Sorry.
不 你不是
No, you're not.
你在做什么 我以为你在伦敦
What are you doing? I thought you were in London.
那是个很疯狂的计划
I mean, it was a mad idea, anyway.
在伦敦都没认识的人
Don't even know anyone in London.
我以为他订票了
I thought he had booked tickets.
没有
No.
那只是为了坐车
No, that was just an act to get a ride.
他连公寓 朋友都没有
He doesn't even have a flat or friends or any of that.
那他现在在哪
So where is he now?
我不知道
I don't know.
他把我留在旅馆里
He left me in a B and B in town.
我们大吵了一架
We had this big row.
他说我不够漂亮不能做模特 而且我还太小
He said I wasn't pretty enough to be a model, and that I was too small.
某种程度是对的 我也很矮
Kinda true. I'm pretty short.
你的脸怎么了
What happened to your cheek?
他打你了吗
Did he hit you?
是的 我活该
Yeah, but I totally deserved it.
你现在要做什么
So what are you gonna do now?
我不知道
I don't know.
我去打印一些简历 但我什么都还没做
I was gonna print some CVs, but I haven't really done anything,
除了你的录像
except your videos.
麦当劳招人
McDonald's have an ad in their window.
如果我去那 你还会喜欢我吗
Would you still fancy me if I did that?
你想要薯片加什么？
"D'you want chips with that?"
只要你高兴
As long as you're happy.
现在这是我的生活了
So that's my life now.
在麦当劳那里工作
Working at McDonald's,
和15岁的学生鬼混
hanging out with a 15-year-old schoolboy.
我果然像我妈妈
I'm exactly like my ma.
我发神经了
I'm mad.
我现在得离开
I have to go now.
我还有场演出要排练
I have a gig to rehearse for.
给我说说
Oh, tell me about that.
不
No.
你也意帮我写首歌吗
Will you help me write a song?
乐意效劳
Always.
♪ I gotta find out... ♪
F调再高点
- F sharp minor. - ♪ Who I'm meant... ♪
E调
- And E. - ♪ To be... ♪
就这样
Just keep doing that.
♪ Don't believe in destiny. ♪
为什么不相信命运
Why doesn't she believe in destiny?
Well...
她总是说要去伦敦
she was always going on about London.
对她来说很重要 就像是自我认同的一部分
It was so important to her, almost like part of her identity.
可能她只是想想
But maybe it was just in her head.
那和她的命运无关
And it wasn't really her destiny at all.
为什么你不带她去伦敦
Why don't you take her to London?
到伦敦的机票多少一张
How much is a plane ticket to London?
好的
Yeah.
乐队怎么办
Anyway, what about the band?
乐队没关系
The band will be fine.
去伦敦 签一份唱片合同
Just go to London and get a record deal.
再回来带我们离开这里
Come back and just get us out of this shithole.
事实上 这不是一个坏主意
That's not a bad idea, actually.
Mm.
♪ You were racin' like a cannonball... ♪
不错
Nice.
是的
Yeah.
钢琴弹得好
Make a nice piano bit.
是的
Yeah.
见鬼
Shit!
把他拿下
Take him down!
抱歉 我不知道你会弹吉他 还有别的
I'm sorry that I didn't know about you playing guitar and everything.
蛮不错的
It's cool.
你不知道的事儿还有很多
There's a lot of stuff you don't know about me.
你也应该 在演出上来一曲
You should come play a solo, at the gig.
可能会的
Okay, I probably will.
你离开这里有一段时间了
You know, it's been a, it's been a while since you've been out of the house.
我现在在这里 不是吗
Well, I'm here now, aren't I?
是的
Okay.
到时候见
So I'll see you there, then.
好的
Yeah. Cool.
听起来蛮有趣
Sounds like it could be fun.
不错
Cool. All right.
等会见
See you later.
她不在这里
Cool, she's not here.
你知道复印机在哪吗
Do you know where the photocopier is?
是的 印200份这个
- Yeah. - Photocopy 200 of these.
为什么
Why?
你会明白的
You'll see.
戴仑 快来
Come on, Darren.
我们还有一件事儿要做
We've got one more thing to do.
这个我来
Now leave this to me.
好的
Yeah.
巴里 那是什么
Who's that, Barry?
是收电视费的吗 叫他离开
If it's the TV license man, tell him to piss off.
你想做什么
What do yous want?
和你谈谈 闭嘴 你个蠢货
- We want to talk to you. - Shut up, you stupid bitch!
巴里你知道吗 你觉得你和我们不一样 你确实不一样
You know what, Barry, you think you're different from us, and you are.
你是让人同情的笨蛋
You're bleedin' nuts.
我们只有一点相似
We all have one thing in common... me, you and him.
都是学校的渣滓 没用的废物
We're all shit at school. We're bleedin' useless.
那又如何 你想做什么
- So? - What are you gonna do
在你退学的时候
when you get kicked out of school?
和你爸妈待在家 看电视虚度光阴
Stay at home with your ma and da watching day-time telly, getting wasted?
是的
Yeah, okay.
我们会组成一个乐队
Well, we're gonna be in a band.
可能会演出
Gigging, on the road.
每晚在不同的场地 不同的女人
Different venues each night, different women.
你知道乐队需要什么吗
And d'you know what bands need?
乐队需要什么
What do bands need?
保镖
Roadies.
强壮会打架的人
Someone who is strong. Someone who can fight.
巴里进来带瓶啤酒过来
Get in here, Barry, and get us another beer!
没用的东西
You worthless shite!
我是没用
I'm a worthless shite.
你把我弄进一个同性恋乐队做什么
I mean, what would you want with me in a fag band?
在乐队里就像在军队
Being in a band is like being in the army.
一方有难 八方支援
Everyone has everyone's back.
你不觉得你可以做到吗
D'you think you're up for it?
巴里进来再待一罐过来 不然你还想挨揍吗
Get in here and get us another can, Barry, or do you want another smack?!
你去哪了
Where do you think you're going?!
回来 小兔崽子
Get back here, you little prick!
不错 该上演一些音乐了
Okay, that was good, but now it's time for some live music.
基佬
Faggots!
都柏林 你好
Hello, Dublin.
我们是来自都柏林的“唱街”
We're Sing Street from Dublin.
基佬
Faggot!
老头子 如果你是来侮辱我们的 你不应该来
Dad, you shouldn't have come here if you're just gonna slag us.
这首歌叫做“女孩们”
This is called "Girls."
♪ Sometimes I pull myself apart ♪
♪ I shift my shape the way I change my colors ♪
♪ Guess I'm a human work of art ♪
♪ A never-ending video-o-o ♪
♪ Truth gets distorted by the facts ♪
♪ Peace is in danger and the trust gets broken ♪
♪ Love always comes under attack ♪
♪ But at the end of all of this ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ All the complicated boys ♪
♪ Boys know that the girls are so complicated ♪
♪ Try to open up your mind ♪
♪ Let go, can you feel your heart liberated ♪
♪ By the complicated boys, boys, boys, boys? ♪
♪ And the complicated girls, girls, girls, girls ♪
♪ We're all just diamonds in the rough ♪
♪ I'm still a stranger in the bathroom mirror ♪
♪ Stare at me long and hard enough ♪
♪ You might see someone that you love ♪
基佬
Faggots!
♪ All the complicated boys, boys know ♪
♪ That the girls are so complicated ♪
♪ Try to open up your mind, let go ♪
♪ Can you feel your heart liberated ♪
♪ By the complicated boys, boys, boys, boys? ♪
♪ And the complicated girls, girls, girls, girls ♪
♪ By the complicated boys, boys, boys, boys ♪
♪ Oh, it's complicated. ♪
一文不值
That was shite!
♪ This girl is a beautiful sea ♪
♪ The girl is a beautiful sea. ♪
谢谢你
Thank you.
好的
Yes.
来吧继续下去
Come on, keep going!
滚下台来
Get off the stage!
下面一首叫 找到你
Okay, here's one called "To Find You."
是一首慢歌
It's a slow song.
我们不是来表演慢歌的
Conor, we're not playing a bleedin' slow song at a gig.
-你疯了吗 -没有
- Are you mad? - No?
他们喜欢我们 那样子会搞砸的
They love us. We'll blow it.
埃蒙
Eamon?
艺高人胆大
I don't know, it's a bold move.
干吧
Let's do it.
这首歌送给每一位 有自己女朋友的人
Okay, this song's for anyone who thought they had a girlfriend
但其实你们只是朋友
for a day, but then she just turned out to be a friend.
关于这些的感觉
What's that about?
♪ When you were starin' at your bedroom wall ♪
♪ With only ghosts beside you ♪
♪ Somewhere out where the wind was calling ♪
♪ I was on my way to find you ♪
♪ When you were racin' like a cannonball ♪
♪ In roller skates and sky blue ♪
♪ Or in the backseat watching the slow rain fallin' ♪
♪ I was on my way to find you ♪
♪ I gotta find out who I'm meant to be ♪
♪ I don't believe in destiny ♪
♪ But with every word you swear to me ♪
♪ All my beliefs start caving in ♪
♪ And I feel something's ♪
♪ About to change ♪
♪ So bring the lightning ♪
♪ Bring the fire, bring the fall ♪
♪ I know I'll get my heart through ♪
♪ Got miles to go ♪
♪ But from the day I started crawlin' ♪
♪ I was on my way to find you ♪
♪ On my way ♪
♪ Every day ♪
♪ I was on my way to find you. ♪
好的
Okay.
这是我们最后一首歌了快回来
So this is our last song, so come back in.
别担心是首快歌
Don't worry, it's a fast one.
是关于这所学校的 关于巴克斯特兄弟
It's about this school, and it's for Brother Baxter.
开灯
Lights!
好 好
Oh, oh, yeah, right.
嘿嘿
Hey! Hey!
灯光就这样
Leave that light switch alone.
你听到我告诉你的了吗
Didn't you hear what I told you?!
Hey!
你觉得这很有趣
You think that's funny?
不要过分了 听到了吗
Don't you push it now, d'you hear me?
这是首致敬的歌
What? It's a tribute song.
下学期还想这个乐队存在的话 最好小心点
If you want to keep this band going next term, you'd better be careful.
好吗好可以
- Okay? - Yeah, okay.
康纳快来
Go on, Conor!
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
这可能是我第一次也是最后一次演出 准备好了吗
This could be all of ours first and last gig, man. You ready to do it?
开始吧
Let's go.
这是我们最后一首歌歌名是“棕色的鞋子”
Okay, so this is our last song. This is called "Brown Shoes,"
写给每一位基督教徒还有你们认识的每一个混蛋
and it's for every Christian Brother and every bully you ever knew.
♪ So who the hell are you to tell me what to do? ♪
♪ You wear a dress and tell me not to wear brown shoes ♪
♪ D'you think you're man enough ♪
♪ To wash the makeup off my face right now? ♪
♪ Don't you know the bigger that they are ♪
♪ The harder they fall? ♪
♪ And the boot's on the other foot now ♪
♪ Buckle up, we're takin' you down ♪
♪ See, your curtain's fallin', so take your bow ♪
♪ And who the hell is he to tell me who to be? ♪
♪ If he wants me dancin', he can watch on MTV ♪
♪ You try to shut me up, I'll turn the volume up ♪
♪ And drown you out ♪
♪ Don't you know the bigger that they are ♪
♪ The harder they fall? ♪
♪ Yeah, the boot's on the other foot now ♪
♪ Buckle up, we're takin' you down ♪
♪ See, your curtain's fallin', so take your bow ♪
♪ What's gonna define the rest of your life? ♪
♪ Start facin' the truth ♪
♪ You're stuck in a lie ♪
♪ Sharp end of your knife is pointing at you ♪
♪ Your up'll be down ♪
♪ Just hangin' around in gravity boots ♪
♪ You're stuck in the past, I'm writing the future ♪
♪ Yeah, the boot's on the other foot now ♪
♪ Buckle up, we're takin' you down ♪
♪ And your mask is slippin', so take your bow ♪
♪ Yeah, you had your time in the sun ♪
♪ Does it hurt when you're kickin' someone? ♪
♪ 'Cause the boot's on the other foot ♪
♪ Boot's on the other foot ♪
♪ Boot's on the other foot now ♪
♪ Take a bow. ♪
谢谢
Thank you!
我们是“唱街”
We're Sing Street!
来自都柏林的“唱街”
That was Sing Street from Dublin.
嘘声音小点
Shh, keep it down.
进来
Come in.
Hi.
Hey.
父母在哪
Where are the parents?
在睡觉 演出怎么样了
They're asleep. How was the gig?
蛮不错的
Great.
Hi.
这是拉菲娜
This is Raphina?
我们需要你帮助
We need your help.
可以载我们去多可利吗
Can you drive us to Dalkey?
为什么
What for?
我祖父的小船还在那里
Well, granddad's little boat is still moored there.
我们要航行到英格兰我们两
We're gonna sail to England, the two of us.
都准备好了到港口前需要一点帮助
We're all set. We just need a lift to the harbor.
当然
Yeah, sure.
你们想什么时候走
When are you thinking of going?
现在
Now.
现在吗
Now?
你在英格兰有认识的人吗
Do you know anybody in England?
-没有 -会掌舵吗
- No. - Do you have any sterling?
不会
No.
-不会吗？ -不会
- No? - No.
她有她的照片
She has her photographs.
我有歌曲小样和录像带
I've my demo tapes and videos.
走吧 去拿钥匙
Let's go. Get the keys.
再见妈妈
I'll see you, Mum.
我爱你
I love you.
都弄好了
All right.
是的
Okay.
你到了后立马打电话给我
You call as soon as you get there.
别忘了 好吗？ 不会忘记
- No messing, all right? - I will.
好吧
Okay.
All right.
嘿 嗯 在你走之前 我
Hey, uh, before you go, I...
写了一些歌词
wrote down some song lyrics.
真的？ 是的
- Really? - Yeah, it's pretty
很意识流的东西 关于一个男孩和一个女孩
stream of consciousness stuff, but it's about this kid and a girl.
在未来的生活
In the future.
某天给歌词配上音乐 不错
- Put some music to it sometime. - Okay.
真希望 我也能这样
Wish I'd done this.
你可能会没命的
You'll probably die.
无论如何 往前看
But anyway, go on.
努力
Go.
你要来看我们
You should come and visit us.
你看起来像个疯子
You seem like a mad bastard.
是吧
Okay.
你照顾好我的兄弟 没有我他会迷路的
You look after that brother of mine. He's gonna be lost without me.
我会的
I will.
今晚打电话给你
Call you tonight.
好的 向前走 继续
Right, go on. Go on.
离开
Away.
好的 所以我们要去岛上 然后一直走
All right, so we're gonna go around the island and straight on.
一直到达威尔士 好吧 一直往前走
Straight to Wales. Okay. Straight on.
一直往前走
Straight on.
All right.
很好
Right.
向前
Forward ho.
太好了
Yes! Yes!
哦
Whoo!
现在你得坐下
You're gonna want to sit down around now.
为什么？
Why?
这就是为什么
That's why.
哦 我的天啊
Oh, my God.
你还好吗？
You okay?
还行
Yeah.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
还好
Yeah.
康纳
Conor!
耶稣啊
Jesus!
哦 我的天啊
Oh, my God.